memolition.com 2015-12-30

# Privacy Policy | memolition

**Introduction**

As a company processing some personal data, we are regulated by the Data Protection Act. This page is intended to keep you informed about what we do with the personal data we process. ‘Personal data’, for the purposes of the Act, means any information which can be used to identify an individual person; it includes things like your name, e-mail address, delivery address, billing address, telephone number and IP address.

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will endeavour to ensure that the information you provide us with is kept private and confidential and is only used to provide the services you request.  **By using this website (the “Site”) and/or our services,  ** **you confirm that you accept this privacy policy and consent to our using your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy.**

We are the data controller for the Site.

**Information we collect**

If you use the Site just to browse the content, we will not collect, store or process any personal data of yours.

If you wish to post a comment, you will need to be signed into a Facebook account and the account name will be displayed above your comment. That name will be stored in our servers for the purpose of such display.

If you submit material to us as a contributor, we will store your name, email address and any other personal information that you supply, for administrative and contact purposes. However, we do not require you to submit any personal information other than your name and email address. If we reject your contribution, we will store your name and email address for a period of up to one year, for archival purposes.

**Cookies**

This site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Site. This helps us to provide you with an enhanced user experience when you browse the Site and improve the Sites functionality. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy. If you do not consent to our using cookies, you can set your browser preferences to block them, but this will affect your use of the Site.

**The Data Protection Act**

We are registered as required under the Data Protection legislation, and we will only process your personal information in line with the principles set out in the Act.

We will process your personal data carefully and lawfully, and will only share them within our organisation and among our employees and appointed representatives, except where we have your explicit consent.

**Security**

We will do our best to protect your personal data using appropriate technical and organisational steps, and will store it on our database within a secure network. However, we cannot absolutely guarantee the security of your personal data.

**Disclosure**

If we reasonably believe that we are required by law to disclose your personal information to a third party, whether in compliance with any applicable law or regulation or by court order or in connection with legal proceedings, we may do so.

Apart from this, we will not disclose or sell your personal information to any third party without your permission. We will not transfer your data outside the European Union except to safe-harbour-certified third parties; this means that the entities to which we send it are certified as having equivalent privacy protection policies as apply within the European Union.

We may use aggregate anonymised data and share it with third parties.

We will not share your personal information with advertisers. However, some of the adverts you may see will be served from locations other than our own server, for example Google Adsense ads.

**Purpose and Duration**

We will use your personal data to:

  1. For  **users who do not leave comments  **on the Site, we will not store any personal information of yours.

  2. For  **users who leave comments**  on the Site, we will not use or disclose your personal information (that is, your email address) but will store it for as long as your comment is displayed below the article under which you left it.

  3. For  **contributors** , we will use your personal information:

  * to send and respond to emails from you

  * to manage our interaction with you

  * to maintain our records and databases;

  * to carry out statistical analysis; and

  * for administration, accounting, marketing and archival purposes.

We will hold your personal information for as long as we need to in order to comply with our legal obligations. You may request for your personal information to be deleted at any time by emailing memolitioncom@gmail.com. Deleted content may persist in backup copies for up to one year, but will not be available to third parties.

**General**

If you wish to find out what data we hold for you, or to have it amended or removed from our database and website, or if you have any questions about this privacy policy, you can contact memolitioncom@gmail.com at any time and we will do so. We may charge a fee for data subject requests.

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time. However, we will not change the way we use your personal information without telling you in advance and giving you the chance to opt out of or prevent the new use of your information.

**COOKIE POLICY**

This website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of this website. This helps us to provide you with an enhanced user experience when you browse this website and improve this websites functionality.

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files that are sent to your computer or mobile device when you visit a site or page. They help the site to recognise your device on future visits.

Cookies have different functions. They can remember your login and preferences, and enhance your user experience in other ways, such as ensuring that the adverts you see are more relevant to you. Some cookies contain personal information: for example, when you click “Remember Me” when you log in to a website, a cookie will be used to store the registration number of the device you are using to access the website.

There are different types of cookies. Essential cookies have functions like recognising that logged-in users can access restricted pages. Functionality cookies remember your preferences while using the website. Performance cookies do not store personal information, but are used to analyse anonymised website usage data. Advertising cookies try to ensure that the adverts you see are tailored to your preferences.

You can block cookies by setting your browser preferences, but this will usually affect how and whether you are able to access the website, especially the restricted areas.
